Now we're going to look at our first big O and I start with O of N, not because it is the most efficient
or least efficient big O, but because I think it's the easiest to explain, easiest one to get your
head around.
So we're going to explain this with some code.
So we're going to create a function that we're going to call print items.
We're going to pass it a number n.
And we're going to have a for loop that runs in times.
And then we're going to print I from the for loop.
Pretty simple.
So let's flip over to VS code and have a look at this.
Okay.
So there is our function.
And then we're going to call it here with the number ten.
So I'm going to run this.
And you can see over here that it printed out zero through nine.
So there were ten items that were printed to the screen.
So let's flip back.
So this is an example of something that is O of n.
We passed it the number n.
And then it ran in time.
So we're in operations.
So whatever N was, that was the number of operations.
So that's O of N.
Let's take a look at this on a graph.
So on this graph on this bottom axis, that's n.
And on the other axis this is the number of operations.
So o of n is always going to be a straight line.
It is what is called proportional.
So if you hear the word proportional when it comes to big O that is going to be O of n.
So we'll be adding to this graph so we can compare one to another.
But for now that is O of n.